ksfcu.org 2019-06-09

# 

                                                                  P.O. Box 9506                                     Rev.1/2015
                                                            Bakersfield, CA 93389-9506
                                                          661.833.7900 or 800.221.3311
                                                                 www.ksfcu.org
                  WHAT DOES KERN SCHOOLS FEDERAL CREDIT UNION DO
 FACTS            WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
 Why?             Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives
                  consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell
                  you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice
                  carefully to understand what we do.
 What?            The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you
                  have with us. This information can include:
                   Social Security number and income
                   account balances and payment history
                   credit history and credit scores
                  When you are no longer our member, we continue to share your information as described in
                  this notice.
 How?             All financial companies need to share members’ personal information to run their everyday
                  business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their
                  members’ personal information; the reasons Kern Schools Federal Credit Union chooses to
                  share; and whether you can limit this sharing.
 Reasons we can share your personal information                              Does Kern Schools   Can you limit this sharing?
                                                                                   Federal
                                                                             Credit Union share?
 For our everyday business purposes --
 such as to process your transactions, maintain
                                                                                     Yes                    No
 your account(s), respond to court orders and legal
 investigations, or report to credit bureaus
 For our marketing purposes --
                                                                                     Yes                    No
 to offer our products and services to you
 For joint marketing with other financial companies                                  Yes                    No
 For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes --
                                                                                     No              We don’t share
 information about your transactions and experiences
 For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes --
                                                                                     No              We don’t share
 information about your creditworthiness
 For nonaffiliates to market to you                                                  No              We don’t share
 Questions?                     Call us at 661.833.7900 or 800.221.3311 or go to www.ksfcu.org.
©2010-2015 Simply Legal - All Rights Reserved CUSTOM 5106 (12M)

Page 2
What we do
How does Kern Schools Federal Credit     To protect your personal information from unauthorized access
Union protect my personal information?   and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law.
                                         These measures include computer safeguards and secured files
                                         and buildings.
How does Kern Schools Federal Credit We collect your personal information, for example when you
Union collect my personal information?  open an account or deposit money
                                          pay your bills or apply for a loan
                                          use your credit or debit card
                                         We also collect your personal information from others, such as
                                         credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.
Why can’t I limit all sharing?           Federal law gives you the right to limit only
                                          sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes -- information
                                            about your creditworthiness
                                          affiliates from using your information to market to you
                                          sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you
                                         State laws and individual companies may give you additional
                                         rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under
                                         state law.
Definitions
Affiliates                               Companies related by common ownership or control. They can
                                         be financial and nonfinancial companies
                                          Kern Schools Federal Credit Union does not share with our
                                            affiliates.
Nonaffiliates                            Companies not related by common ownership or control. They
                                         can be financial and nonfinancial companies
                                          Kern Schools Federal Credit Union does not share with
                                            nonaffiliates so they can market to you.
Joint marketing                          A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies
                                         that together market financial products or services to you.
                                          Our joint marketing partners include investment, insurance,
                                            mortgage bankers and other financial companies.
Other important information
California law provides that a consumer has the right to control the sharing of personal and financial
information with outside companies the financial institution contracts with to provide financial products
and services. To exercise your right, refer to the separate notice titled, “Important Privacy Choices for
Consumers” which is provided to you by Kern Schools Federal Credit Union.

                                                                     Important
                                                                             Privacy
                                                                            C hoices
                                                                     for     Consumers
                                                                      Your Records Are Safe  with  Us
                                                                             P.O. Box 9506
                                                                       Bakersfield, CA 93389-9506
                                                                      661.833.7900 or 800.221.3311
              ©2004-2013 Simply Legal- All Rights Reserved
                                                                             www.ksfcu.org
CUSTOM 5107 (89M)    		                                    PTD 12/13

Important Privacy Choices for             Time Sensitive Reply
              Consumers                   You may make your privacy choice at any
                                          time. Your choice marked here will remain
You have the right to control whether     unless you state otherwise. However, if
we share some of your personal            we do not hear from you we may share
information. Please read the following    some of your information with other
information carefully before you make     companies with whom we have contracts
your choice below.                        to provide products and services.
Your Rights                               To exercise your choice do one of the
                                          following:
You have the following right to restrict
the sharing of personal and financial     • Complete the information below, sign
information with outside companies           and send back this form to us using the
that we do business with. Nothing in this    envelope provided (you may want to
form prohibits the sharing of information    make a copy for your records).
necessary for us to follow the law, as    • Call us toll-free at 800.221.3311 or our
permitted by law, or to give you the best    local telephone number at 661.833.7900.
service on your accounts with us. This    • Contact us at www.ksfcu.org by logging
includes sending you information about       on to the website's online home
some other products or services.             banking link. Enter your user name and
                                             password. Then, click on the CA SB-1
Your Choice                                  Privacy link located at the bottom of the
Restrict Information Sharing With Other      web page and enter your privacy choice.
Companies We Do Business With To
Provide Financial Products and Services:
Unless you say “No,” we may share
personal and financial information about
you with outside companies we contract
with to provide financial products and
services to you.                          Member/Joint Owner Name (please print)
    NO, please do not share personal      Account Number(s)
and financial information with outside     X
companies you contract with to provide    Member/Joint Owner Signature		         Date
financial products and services.

Children’s Privacy Policy
Kern Schools Federal Credit Union’s financial services offered through its website are not designed or
directed toward children under age 13. The Credit Union has established the following privacy policy in
accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998:
To benefit the youth Members of KSFCU, the Credit Union established the Rocky Raccoon and Kappa
account programs. These programs are designed to educate and inform the children of Kern Schools’
Members on saving for the future.
Information Collected:
Kern Schools does not knowingly solicit or collect data from children, and we do not knowingly market
to children online. If we receive online information from anyone that we know to be a child, we will only
use the information provided to respond directly to a child’s request.
Site Traffic and Cookies:
Kern Schools collects statistical information on the time, frequency, and duration of visits to our web
site. The gathered information does not contain personal identifiers. Website visitor information is not
sold or given to third parties. Cookies are information files that the web browser places on the hard
drive of the user’s computer when a web site is visited. Cookie files are not used to collect personal
information and they are not required to navigate Kern Schools’ web site. Kern Schools encourages
parents to monitor and participate in online activity with their youth to ensure their children have a fun,
safe, and educational experience. If you have any questions or comments regarding our children’s
privacy policy, please send your inquiries to:
Kern Schools Federal Credit Union
Compliance Department
P O Box 9506
Bakersfield, CA 93389
(800) 221-3311 ext. 7032
Rev.03/2015
